<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!-- generator="FEEDCREATOR_VERSION" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:sns="http://blog.sina.com.cn/sns">
    <channel>
        <title>Shane Battier,Rockets</title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/battier</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 16:54:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>FEEDCREATOR_VERSION</generator>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 1996 - 2009 SINA Inc. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 15:12:12 +0800</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title>我会想念休斯顿 现在开始新一轮冒险的时候到了！</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e01017vvx.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>SHANE BATTIER<br />
Peak Blog<br />
February 25, 2011</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>As I sit here in a Memphis hotel, I still have a difficult time
believing that I am back as a Memphis Grizzly! When I left here 5
years ago, I was convinced that I had played my last game as a
Grizz. In the NBA, you just don't have second tours with the same
team. It is very rare. Whenever I played the Grizzlies as a Rocket,
I had always received a great ovation from the fans in Memphis.
There were always numerous signs that said "Come back Shane!!!!!"
It made me laugh, but at the same time, it made me feel great to
know that I had touched so many people in my 5 years in
Memphis.</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>I did not know for sure if I was going to be traded from the
Rockets. I thought there was a good possibility, but I just didn't
know. I was very nervous the entire day. I paced around my house
and played with my dogs, just trying to waste time and make it past
the 2 pm trade deadline. I checked my computer every 10 minutes to
see if I had been traded and must have checked my phone at least
100 times!!!!!!! At 1:45, I had not heard anything about a trade. I
had started to believe that I was not going to be traded. At 1:55,
pm, 5 minutes before the trade deadline, I checked the computer one
last time. In big headlines, the screen read: Shane Battier traded
to the Memphis Grizzlies. I could NOT believe it. My initial
reaction was shock and then I started to think of all the things I
would need to do before I left. To make matters worse, my wife
Heidi and son Zeke, were not even home. They were returning from
Detroit where they came to visit me as the Rockets played the
Detroit Pistons. When I called her, she didn't even believe me.</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>I was sad because I would not be able to play any more games
with my teammates, my friends. Guys like Chuck Hayes, Luis Scola,
Chase Budinger, my guys. We have been through so many battles
together. I was sad that I would not finish what we started and
tried to make one last playoff push. I had 5 wonderful years in
Houston. I won a lot of games there and played with some great
players. To know that this part of my life is over makes you a tad
sad. I want to thank all of my friends and fans in Houston for
their unwavering support of me over the last 5 years. I will miss
these relationships, but am a better person because of my 5 years
in Houston.</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>It was only until my phone exploded with text messages and
emails from my friends in Memphis telling me how excited they were
that I was coming back to Memphis, did I start to look forward to
coming back to the Grizzlies. People were genuinely excited and it
really brought a smile to my face. When I left Memphis 5 years ago,
I was always regretful that I was not able to win a playoff game
for the Grizzlies despite making the playoffs 3 times. I left
Memphis 0-12 in the playoffs. This did not make me happy. I am so
excited to get a chance to lead the Grizzlies back to the playoffs
and win some games!!!! There is nothing better than settling
unfinished business.</P>
<p>There is no question I will miss my friends in Houston, but my
friends in Houston are excited for a potential playoff run in
Memphis. I am thankful for my 5 years in Houston. It is time for a
new adventure! Stay tuned!</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>SB</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
当我坐在孟菲斯的酒店屋里的时候，我还是有些难以置信我回到了孟菲斯。五年前，我离开这里，我就努力让自己接受这是我在灰熊打的最后一场比赛的事实。因为一般来说在NBA，是很难有第二次机会为同一支球队效力的。这种情况非常罕见。而不论何时，甚至是我代表火箭同灰熊比赛的时候，我都能在这里享受到球迷们的欢迎。总会有很多标语写着“欢迎回来，肖恩！”这让我很开心，也让我意识到在灰熊的5年中我也曾经令这里的人感动过。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
这一次，我之前并不知道我会被火箭交易走。我只是觉得有可能性而已。所以那一天我非常紧张，我在自己的家里来回踱步，遛狗，就是为了消磨时间，挺过下午2点——交易截止期。我每10分钟就会看一下我的电脑，但有没有我被交易的消息，然后检查手机100次！！！！！在1点45的时候，我还没有听到任何关于这次交易的消息。我开始觉得我可能不会被交易了。到了1点55，也就是距离交易截止还有5分钟的时候，我最后一次查看了电脑。头条，屏幕上显示：肖恩-巴蒂尔被交易到孟菲斯灰熊。我真的不敢相信。我的第一反应是震惊，然后开始想在我离开之前我需要做的事情。更糟糕的情况是，我的妻子海蒂和儿子齐克当时都不在家。他们去底特律了，当火箭客场打活塞的时候他们还看过我。当我给她打电话的时候，她也无法相信我说的事实。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
我很伤心，因为我不能再和我的队友们、我的朋友们一起打球了。像海耶斯、斯科拉、巴丁格，都是我的哥们。我们在一起战斗过太多次了。我很伤心没法和他们一起为了最初的目标继续奋斗继续冲击季后赛。我在休斯顿度过了5年精彩的时光。我在这赢得过很多次胜利，和很多伟大的球员一起打过球。当我意识到我生活中这一部分内容即将结束的时候，非常非常地伤心。我想感谢所有我的休斯顿球迷和朋友们，因为他们在过去的5年中毫不动摇地支持我。我会怀念这段时光，因为在这5年的休斯顿生活中，我变成了一个更好的人。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
然后，我的手机就爆炸了，在孟菲斯的朋友们开始不停地给我发短信告诉我他们对我能回到那有多么兴奋。问我是不是期待回到灰熊。看到人们这样兴奋，我的脸上才重新绽放出微笑。当我5年前离开孟菲斯的时候，我一直对于没能帮灰熊ing赢得一次季后赛的胜利而耿耿于怀，尽管当时我们3次进入了季后赛。我在孟菲斯的季后赛记录是0胜12负。这让我不开心。所以现在得到带领灰熊重新杀回季后赛并且赢下一些比赛的机会的时候，我又开始兴奋了！！！！！再没有什么比这些不确定的挑战更好的事情了。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
毫无疑问我会想念休斯顿的朋友们，但是火箭和灰熊将为了季后赛名额产生一番竞争。我感觉过去5年休斯顿的生活。现在，是开始新一轮冒险的时候了！加油！</P>
<p>肖恩-巴蒂尔</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e01017vvx.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 16:54:31 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e01017vvx.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>中国之行</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100m1xs.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static14.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et931766e40a8d" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static14.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253et931766e40a8d&amp;690" WIDTH="550" HEIGHT="393" /></A><br />
<br />
<p>
　　中国之行非常棒！我和队友在两场中国赛期间度过了一段愉快的时光。中国球迷用山呼海啸的热情欢迎我们。毫无疑问，火箭是在中国最有人气的一支
NBA球队。北京很有趣。一大亮点是我们全队去了秀水市场。看到一群NBA球员过来逛街，所有的摊贩都惊呆了。造成了一些混乱。我领略了路易斯-斯科拉谈
判专家的风采，他做成了几笔不错的生意。杰弗里斯买了一顶中国战斗机飞行员的头盔，在中国期间，他成天都戴着。他太搞了，看上去就像一个白痴。我们的日程
非常紧，根本没时间好好观光，但逛秀水市场绝对是个亮点。一些队员还去了长城。我看了他们拍摄的视频。在长城上，你可以开一辆小车下山。车速非常快，帕特
森不太会刹车，让他的车子几乎翻出了轨道。他把全过程都拍摄了下来。真是搞笑。</P>
<p>
　　这趟旅行最疯狂的部分是姚明在北京和广州街头引起的骚动。他们一见到他，就立刻疯狂起来。在那个星期里，我看到了有成百上千的姚明头像。毫无疑
问，他是中国的骄子。我不知道如果我和知名度和姚明一样，我是否能够应付。我不知道如果每天有那么多人围着我给我拍照，我是否还能保持冷静和风度。我没有
这种体会。姚明在宣传活动中保持着谦逊和优雅，他这方面的能力令人不可思议。他是独一无二的。</P>
<p>
　　我们和篮网的第一场比赛安排在五棵松奥运会球馆。球馆的外型太酷了。让我们想起了自己的主场丰田中心。两者很像。球迷相当投入。通常季前赛的气氛有些沉闷，因为球迷并没有真正投入，但在北京和广州不是这样。</P>
<p>
　　四年前的夏天，我受匹克的邀请去了一趟广州。我不敢相信广州这四年来的变化。整个市区焕然一新，满眼都是新起的高楼。我知道为了迎接亚运会盖了不少楼，但广州的发展速度还是令我印象深刻。</P>
<p>
　　姚明在北京受到热情欢迎，而到了广州，他让我感觉像是在跟披头士或迈克尔-杰克逊一起办巡回演唱。广州以身为中国篮球中心而自豪，欣然他们
非常喜爱篮球。太疯狂了。在我们结束了训练之后，大家跟着我们大巴一起跑过三个街区。我们所有队员都拿着自己的摄像机或手机拍摄下这一幕。</P>
<p>
　　在广州，我们又和篮网打了一场，地点是新建的、漂亮的亚运球馆。在我所有打过的球场中，这个令我印象非常深刻。这里的球迷也非常棒。他们为
NBA篮球而疯狂。也许这能解释为什么我竟然上演了<a HREF="http://video.sina.com.cn/p/sports/k/v/2010-10-16/211361160945.html" TARGET="_blank">一记职业生涯最佳扣篮</A>。姚明当时底线投篮不中，我跟上前去用一记补扣震惊了全场每个人，也包括我自己，
哈哈。</P>
<p>
　　这是一趟非凡的中国之行。我要感谢每个给予热情欢迎我们的人。这是我第七次前往中国，但和球队一起去，这是头一遭，我敢说中国给每个队友都留下了新的美好印象，尤其是举国上下对于篮球的热爱。这是我在NBA多年以来最棒的篮球体验！</P>
<p>　　保重，回见，</P>
<p>　　肖恩</P>
<p>　　原文如下——</P>
<p>　　10.20.10</P>
<p>　　What a great trip to China! My teammates and I had a fantastic
time playing two exhibition games in China. The reception that we
received from Chinese basketball fans was overwhelming. There is
little doubt that the Rockets are the favorite NBA team in China.
Beijing was a lot of fun. One of the highlights was taking a team
trip to the Silk Market. All of the vendors were going crazy with a
bunch of NBA players walking around. It was pandemonium. I learned
that Luis Scola is a master negotiator, he got some great deals.
Jared Jefferies bought a Chinese fighter pilot's helmet and wore it
around the entire time we were in China. He's a funny guy, and he
looked like an idiot. Our schedule was very tight, so we didn't
have much time to do sightseeing, but the Silk Market was a great
highlight. Some of my teammates went to see the Great Wall north of
Beijing. I saw some great videos of my teammates. At the Great
Wall, you can take a small cart to the bottom of the hill. The
carts actually get going fast. Patrick Patterson didn't use his
brakes very well and nearly flipped his cart right off the track.
He captured the whole thing on video. It was hilarious。</P>
<p>　　The craziest part of the trip, by far, was the reaction to Yao
Ming on the streets of Beijing and Guangzhou. People flipped out
when they saw him. There had to be over hundreds of thousands of
pictures taken of Yao during the week. He is the favorite son of
China, no doubt. I don't know if I could deal with the level of
fame that Yao must face daily. I don't think I could keep my
politeness if I had to deal with the constant stream of people
grabbing and photographing me. I have never seen anything like it.
Yao does an unbelievable job of handling the publicity with
humility and grace. He's one of a kind。</P>
<p>　　We played the New Jersey Nets at the Olympic basketball
stadium. What a cool looking stadium. It reminded me of the Toyota
Center where we play our home games. It was very similar. The crowd
was electric and really into the game. Usually preseason games are
boring because the crowd is not really into the game, but that was
not the case in Beijing and Guangzhou。</P>
<p>　　I went to Guangzhou four years ago as part of my summer tour
with Peak. I couldn't believe the change in city in four years. It
looked completely new with all of the new buildings. I know that
there was a lot of construction for the Asian Games, but I was
really impressed with the growth of Guangzhou。</P>
<p>　　While Yao received a great reception in Beijing, I felt like I
was touring with the Beatles and Michael Jackson rolled into one
with Yao in Guangzhou.&nbsp; Guangzhou prides
themselves as being the center of Chinese basketball and it was
obvious they really loved basketball. It was crazy. People were
running after our bus for 3 city blocks after our practice in
Guangzhou one day. Our entire team had their cameras and cell
phones out recording the whole episode。</P>
<p>　　We played the Nets again in the new beautiful basketball
center in Guangzhou that they built for the Asian Games. It was as
impressive of a stadium that I have ever played in. The crowd was
great again. They were fired up for some NBA basketball. Perhaps
that explained why I had one of the best dunks of my career in this
game. Yao missed a shot on the baseline and I followed it up with a
sweet tip dunk that surprised everyone in the gym, including me,
ha。</P>
<p>　　It was a fantastic trip to China. I want to thank everyone for
their hospitality. It was my seventh time to China, but the first
time with my team and I can say that everyone left with a new
appreciation for China, and the country's love of basketball. It
was definitely one of best basketball experiences I have had in the
NBA!</P>
<p>　　Take care and talk to you soon,</P>
<p>　　Shane</P>
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100m1xs.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 10:36:57 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100m1xs.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>祝贺姚明和叶莉</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100ila5.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p STYLE="TexT-inDenT: 2em">
虽然我现在正在小岛上度假，但仍旧要为姚明和他的妻子叶莉送上祝福，他们的小女儿出生啦！我知道对于升级做父母他们都很兴奋，并且都能够成为好爸爸和好妈妈。我很兴奋，迫不及待想见见他们家庭的新成员。祝贺你们，姚明和叶莉！</P>
<p STYLE="TexT-inDenT: 2em">&nbsp;</P>
<p STYLE="TexT-inDenT: 2em">Although I am currently in the islands
for vacation right now, I want to offer my congratulations to Yao
Ming and his wife Ye Li on the birth of their daughter! I know they
are both excited to become parents and will do a great job. I am
excited to meet the newest addition to their family.
Congratulations to Yao and Ye Li!</P>]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100ila5.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 12:19:47 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100ila5.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>晒晒我的暑假生活！</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100i96p.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static2.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et865e7a11f2f1" TARGET="_blank"><img HEIGHT="517" SRC="http://static2.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253et865e7a11f2f1&amp;690" WIDTH="690" NAME="image_operate_86161273640250109" /></A></P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
嗨！大家好。我又来跟大家汇报我的暑期生活了。赛后结束后的前几周我还挺忙的，因为赛季中的时候我没有太多的时间去做我想做的事情，所以我把他们全都安排在赛季结束了。这几周我就好比在休假之前整理了自己的办公桌，把那些不用的文件都清理干净。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
休季期最美好的事情不过于和我儿子齐克还有妻子海蒂一起共度的日子了。儿子在6月份马上就要满2周岁了，他会带他到海滩上，让他在沙滩上享受大海。他特别喜欢水，像条小鱼似的。我热爱篮球，非常幸运能在NBA打球，不过我依然非常享受和家人一起度假、每天喝几杯红酒、在沙滩上放松的时刻。</P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
我的太太和我准备趁着奶奶来帮忙照顾齐克的一段时间去加勒比海的小岛上去杜度假，我已经有点迫不及待了。能在海滩呆上一周，看看书，品尝美食，喝点小酒，太惬意了。现在就是度假时间！所有在赛季中的受的伤，希望都能够在这次假期中得到彻底的缓解！我已经等不及了。</P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
海蒂和我最近还去看了一个世界知名的赛马大赛，名字叫肯塔基德比赛，我以前从来没去看过，这次看得很过瘾。和我们同去的还有我最好的朋友，印第安纳步行者队的麦克-邓利维和他的妻子。这次有趣，因为每天都要梳妆打扮好去看赛马，我非常兴奋，还有几次押对了最后获胜的马。</P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
还有一件事情我得告诉你们，我的膝盖已经感觉好多了，这段时间我会集中注意力让膝盖得以放松，再陪伴我的家人！很不错的计划把！</P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
同时，给大家看看我们暑假拍的几张照片。</P>
<p><a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static2.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et865e7a11f2f1" TARGET="_blank"></A><br />
<br />
<a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static13.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et865e7a7cb0fc" TARGET="_blank"><img HEIGHT="517" SRC="http://static13.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253et865e7a7cb0fc&amp;690" WIDTH="690" /></A><br />
<br />
<a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static13.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et865e7ad851fc" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static13.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253et865e7ad851fc&amp;690" />
</A><br />
<br /></P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 回聊</P>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 肖恩</P>
<p>Hey everyone, I just wanted to update you on my summer so far.
The first couple of weeks after the season is usually pretty busy.
I don't have much time during the season for many of the things I
would like to get done, so I put them off until the season is
complete. Things like cleaning out my office and organizing files
are the boring tasks that get completed in the first few weeks
after the season. The best part of the offseason is being able to
hang out with my son Zeke and my wife Heidi. We took my son, who
will be 2 in June, to the beach and watched him play in the ocean
and in the sand. He's like a fish, he loves the water. I love
basketball and I am lucky to play in the NBA, but I also enjoy my
vacation time with my family and enjoy having a few glasses of wine
and relaxing at the beach. My wife and I are getting ready to go on
our vacation to the Caribbean islands while Grandma is coming to
watch Zeke. I can't wait. A week of sitting at the beach, reading
books, eating fantastic meals and drinking some nice wine. Now that
is a vacation! All the bumps and bruises that I have during the
season fully heal on vacations like this. I can't wait.</P>
<p><br />
Heidi and I also went to one of the most famous horse races in the
world called the Kentucky Derby. I had never been before, and had a
great time. I went with my best friend and his wife, Mike Dunleavy
of the Indiana Pacers. Its a fun event because you get to dress up
and watch the horse races every day. It was exciting and I even
picked a few of the winning horses. ha.燑/div&gt;</P>
<p><br />
Just wanted to give you a quick update on my summer. My knee is
healing and feels great again. I am just focused on relaxing and
spending time with my family right now. Good
stuff.燑/div&gt;</P>
<p><br />
Here are a few pictures of the summer so far.</P>
<p><br />
Talk to you soon<br />
Shane</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100i96p.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 12:56:08 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100i96p.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>火箭这一季</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100hnay.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static12.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et843e4eb1eebb" TARGET="_blank"><img HEIGHT="397" SRC="http://static12.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253et843e4eb1eebb&amp;690" WIDTH="594" /></A><br />
<br />
首先，我要向青海地震灾民表达我的问候。我知道不久之前中国四川就曾经发生过类似的灾难。请大家一起为灾民们祈福！中国人民拥有超强的韧劲。尽管再次面对命运的考验令人有些难以接受，但我相信中国人民能够战胜灾难。<br />

<br />
今天我们将迎来赛季的最后一场比赛：对阵黄蜂。这个赛季我们已经获得了42场胜利，确保了最终的胜率高于50%。我觉得大多数人可能不能认为我们球员和教练通过努力获得42胜是一个成就。错了，这是一个伟大的成就。许多人赛季初都认为我们不可能达到这个高度，他们都把目光聚焦在我们的短板上，在注意我们的缺点，但对于那些更衣室里、午夜航班、疲惫的长途大巴上的我们来说，回顾这个赛季，记得的将是：不断的厮杀和将大家团结在一起的力量。<br />

<br />
没有姚明，没有麦蒂，没有了7英尺巨人，伤病侵袭，残酷的赛程，身处西部，没有全明星球员，赛季中的大交易，所有这些都反过来印证了这个赛季的伟大。不错。应该说很不错。在NBA只有5、6支球队有机会赢得总冠军。很多球迷都抱着这样的心态(套用里奇-鲍比的话)“如果你不是第一，就是倒数第一。”我为这样的球迷感到遗憾，因为你错过了一些精彩的旅程。克服逆境取得成功，给你带来的快感不亚于获得总冠军。当然了，如果能够克服逆境并夺得总冠军，那是最好，但这不是享受整个赛季的唯一方式。<br />

<br />
当初，很多人认为我们的战绩会和一些传统弱旅差不多，但我们一直是季后赛席位的有力争夺者，直到最近才掉队。<br />
<br />
至于个人的表现，我也觉得很满足。职业生涯到了今天，我不再关心数据上的突破。这根本没什么。说实话，把自己职业生涯平均分提高4、5分，这并不会让我个人、教练或队友感到开心。所以，只有一项数据是应该在乎的：那就是胜场！我认为自己竭尽全力帮助球队取得胜利。我本希望自己能投进更多三分，获得更高的罚球命中率，但没办法事与愿违。今年我第一次成为了更衣室中的“老人”。我努力每天在训练馆营造出一种积极的氛围，为新人老人们树立榜样。我希望我的态度和这种想法能够渗透给全队。你们肯定都不知道，但是这是我真实的想法。在防守上，我也作出了改变，因为我的身后没有能经常盖帽的大个子了（我现在是球队中最厉害的盖帽手……亚克西！）所以，我现在不得不去用一些更传统的方式去防守。我最想推翻的一项NBA奖项就是“最佳防守球员”，这其实是一个谬论，因为他们根本就不存在。他们能够成功，多是因为他们身后存在着能“盖帽”的伟大球员。哈！姚！穆大叔！回来吧!<br />

<br />
我认为自己很坚强。<br />
<br />
所以，当我们告别09－10赛季时，我会记得的是，虽然从一开始就不被看好，但我们拼得有多凶。尽管没拿到总冠军，但这段旅程依然甜蜜。<br />

<br />
肖恩<br />
<br />
原文如下——<br />
<br />
First of all, I want to send my prayers and thoughts to the people
of the Qinghai province. I know that is was not too long ago that
China felt the devastation in the Sichuan Province. Please send
your prayers with the people of this terrible disaster. The Chinese
people have shown they are extremely resilient. It is difficult to
continue to be tested, but I have faith that the Chinese people
will overcome this.<br />
<br />
Getting ready to play the New Orleans Hornets in the season finale.
We just won our 42nd game of the year, ensuring us a winning record
for the year. I don’t think most people can appreciate the efforts
of our players and coaches that we put in to win 42 games. A
winning record for a team that went through the adversity that we
went through is not a good accomplishment, it’s a great
accomplishment. While most people will look at this year and lament
at what we failed to accomplish and focus on our shortcomings as a
team, for those who were in the locker room and on all the late
flights and tired bus rides will look back on this year and
remember the scrapping, clawing, and energy it took to keep us a
relevant team.<br />
<br />
No Yao, no McGrady, No 7 footers, injuries, brutal scheduling,
playing in the Western Conference, no all-stars, a huge mid-season
trade and all we have to show for it is a winning season. Not bad.
Not bad at all. Realistically in the NBA, only a handful, maybe 5
or 6 teams have a legitimate shot to win the title. Many fans get
caught up in the attitude (to paraphrase Ricky Bobby) “if you’re
not first, your last.” I feel sorry for the people who believe this
because you sometimes miss the incredible journey that you find
yourself on. Overcoming adversity and succeeding in spite of it,
can bring you as much satisfaction in the task at hand as a
championship can. Obviously, overcoming adversity AND winning a
championship trumps all, but it’s not the only way to enjoy a
season.<br />
<br />
Most people picked us to finish amongst the perennial lottery
teams, and we kept our name in the playoff race until the waning
weeks of the season.<br />
<br />
For me personally, I felt fulfilled. At this point in my career, I
could care less about statistical achievement. It simply doesn’t
matter. Averaging 4 or 5 more points above my career average would
not make me any happier nor my coaches or teammates to be honest.
At this point, there is only one stat that matters: Wins! I thought
I did everything in my control to prepare myself and my teammates
to win games. I would have liked to make a few more 3’s, and shot a
higher percentage at the free throw line but things like that just
happen. This was the first year that I was the senior in the locker
room. I tried to bring a positive attitude to the gym every day,
both as an example for the young guys and the veterans.I’d like to
think that my attitude and resolve rubbed off. You never know, but
I’d like to think so at least. Defensively, my whole attitude had
to change without the threat of shotblocking behind me (I was the
team’s leading shotblocker……yikes!). I had to play a much more
conservative style of defensive. My favorite fallacy in the NBA is
the existence of a ‘lockdown’ defender. They don’t exist anymore.
There are only very good defenders with GREAT shotblocking behind
them. Ha. Yao, Deke come back! Ha.<br />
<br />
I thought I was solid under the circumstances.<br />
<br />
So as we close the door on the 09-10 season, I’ll look back and
remember how hard we fought when we were counted out from the
beginning. It might not be a championship, the journey was still
sweet.<br />
<br />
Shane<br />
<br />
<br />]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100hnay.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 05:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100hnay.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>坏消息</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100h8iu.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a HREF="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static8.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et828357d68b57" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static8.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253et828357d68b57&amp;690" /></A><br />

<br />
今天我要告诉大家一些坏消息。几天前在迎战纽约尼克斯时，我的队友洛瑞上篮时遭遇犯规，令他失去平衡，倒向人堆，我的左腿被他们撞了一下。尽管我的脚很快就恢复了，但膝盖扭了。我很快就感到一阵巨疼，随即倒地。这是我职业生涯最最恐怖的时刻，因为我知道膝盖有多脆弱。尽管膝盖受伤了，但我本能地爬起来继续比赛。队友阿里扎抢断后传球给我。我忍着膝盖的疼痛还是把球投了出去。就像我说的，这时候整个人完全被本能接管。我投篮不中后立刻抢下篮板，就在想把球传给队友乔丹-希尔之际，对手对我犯规了，我再次倒地。队友上前要拉我起来，我跟他们说“给我一分钟，我想看看膝盖是不是还在。”队友可能觉得我在开玩笑，因为我以前倒地后很快就能起来。有些人意识到我真的受伤了，因为他们发现我眼神中有一种从未见过的、异样的东西。我很害怕。接着我走上罚球线，第二罚没中，这让我很难过，因为在我们队中流传一种说法，如果你受伤时连罚球都罚不中，那说明你不够强悍，哈哈。接下来我对一名尼克斯队员犯规，很快就下场回到了休息室，等待队医对我进行检查。<br />

<br />
我祈祷膝盖的每一根韧带都完好无损，没有一根断裂，不需要手术。一个医生走进来看了下我的膝盖，他认为我的膝盖没事儿，不过膝盖内侧的一根韧带拉伤了。我很高兴听到这个消息，尽管还需要接受核磁共振检查才能确诊。<br />

<br />
第二天到了芝加哥，我接受了核磁共振检查，伤情得到了确诊，的确是内侧韧带拉伤。我真的觉得这是好消息。拉伤的情况很多时候都会自然康复，不需要接受手术，而手术是我最害怕的。我的膝盖依然很疼，但还好伤情没有更严重。<br />

<br />
我可能将缺席2－4周。我很失望，因为我本赛季原本想打81场(之前曾缺席一场常规赛--注)，在受伤前我觉得身体状况非常好。我的缺阵将让巴丁格获得更多的上场时间和比赛经验。我将在替补席上学着做一名教练，支持我的球队，你必须随时调整自己的角色。我们还有13场比赛，我们必须要创造奇迹才能杀入季后赛。机会不在我们这一边，但你永远不知道联盟中会发生什么。<br />

<br />
我很抱歉和大家分享这个坏消息，但没有风雨怎能见到彩虹？我很乐观，相信自己能够很快回到场上，相信这次受伤不会影响我的状态。<br />
<br />
回见，<br />
<br />
肖恩<br />
<br />
全文如下<br />
<br />
I have some bad news to share with you today. While playing the New
York Knicks a few days ago, my teammate Kyle Lowry drove to the
hoop and was fouled and knocked off balance. He collided into a few
Knicks players and the whole pile of players collided right into my
left knee. Unfortunately, my foot was planted at the time and my
knee bowed to the side. I immediately felt pain on the side of my
knee and fell to the ground. It was one of the scariest moments of
my career because I know how fragile knees can be. Although my knee
hurt, I instinctively rose up and continued to play. Trevor Ariza,
my teammate, stole the ball and passed it to me. Although I knew my
knee was injured I still shot the ball. Like I said, instinct took
over. I then followed my shot and got the rebound and passed to my
teammate Jordan Hill, but before I could get the pass off, I was
fouled and went to the ground again. When my teammates rushed over
to help me up, I told them "Just give me a minute, I have to figure
out if my knee was still in place." I think my teammates thought I
was joking because I always bounce up when I go to the ground. Some
of my teammates knew that I was injured because I had a look in my
eye that they had not seen before. I was scared. I shot the free
throws, I actually missed the second one which made me mad because
its a running joke on our team that if you miss free throws when
you are hurt, you must not be that tough, haha. I fouled one of the
Knicks players and immediately ran off the court to the locker room
where I waited for the team doctors to check me out.<br />
<br />
I was praying and hoping that all of the ligaments in my knee were
intact and that nothing was torn or needed surgery. When the doctor
came in and examined my knee, he thought that my knee was stable,
but I had sprained the MCL, which is the ligament on the inside of
your knee. I was relieved to hear this news, although I wanted an
MRI to confirm what the doctor thought.<br />
<br />
In Chicago, the next day I had an MRI that confirmed that I indeed
had sprained the MCL. I actually thought this was great news.
Sprains heal themselves over time and do not require surgery, which
was my biggest fear. My knee is still very sore, but it could have
been much, much worse.<br />
<br />
It looks like I will miss the next 2-4 weeks. I am disappointed
that I became injured because I was looking forward to playing 81
games this year and I felt physically great before the knee injury.
This will give the opportunity for Chase Budinger to play more and
get more experience. I will do my best to be a coach on the
sideline and support my team, you have to try to make the best of
your situation. We have 13 games left and we need to have a great
record to make a push for the playoffs. The odds are not in our
favor, but you just never know what's going to happen in this
league.<br />
<br />
I am sorry I have to share bad news with you today, but without
some rainy days, how can you appreciate the sunny ones? I am
optimistic that I will return soon and have no long lasting effects
of this injury.<br />
<br />
Talk to you soon,<br />
<br />
shane<br />
<br />]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100h8iu.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 11:14:40 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100h8iu.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>“Consistency”</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100gzyw.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a HREF="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static6.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253eg815444492485" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static6.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253eg815444492485&amp;690" /></A><br />

<br />
现在整个赛季已经过去了3/4。我们还剩下20场比赛。目前我们的战绩是31胜31负。不多不少正好50％。有人问我，对于目前的战绩是否感到失望。我的回答很简单，也对也不对。哈。显而易见，当你回顾这个赛季，你开始计算我们输了多少场本该拿下的比赛。你会发现许多由于心理问题或低级失误葬送掉的胜利。每支球队回顾整个赛季时都会发现一些这样的遗憾场次。问题是：我们队这样的比赛多到我数不过来。我绝不会现在就缴械。我们还有20场比赛要打。你永远不知道什么时候幸运之神会光顾，所以我们必须继续拼搏，努力赢下每场比赛。<br />

<br />
目前更紧迫的目标是重新找回比赛的“稳定性”。我们最近有好几场酣畅淋漓的胜利，比赛就像经过精密计算一样。我们的防守出色，投篮有准星，打出了团队篮球。不幸的是，我们每打完一场这样的比赛，接下来就会有一场臭球。我不知道原因是什么，反正我们就是起起伏伏。在我们努力融合凯文-马丁、希尔顿-阿姆斯特朗、乔丹-希尔和杰弗里斯等新队友时，依然要注意保持稳定的发挥。我想当我回顾整个赛季时，也许最让我失望的就是这个方面。我坚定地信奉一个准则：你必须做自己最擅长的事情，拿出你的能量和团队精神，日复一日，抓住机会。如果你的战术体系和球员足够好的话，你就能赢球；反之，则不能，但更重要的是：你必须都让自己每天的水平保持在一个基准之上。我们还在寻找这条“基准线”。<br />

<br />
我希望我们在最后20场比赛中能找到自己的步伐节奏。我希望我们能建立起自信。如果今年没能成功，至少得为下个赛季的爆发攒一点气势。这是我们常规赛最后一个月的目标。<br />

<br />
回见，<br />
<br />
肖恩<br />
<br />
原文如下——<br />
<br />
We are standing at the 3/4 point of the season. We have 20 games to
go. We are 31-31. Exactly at .500. I get asked if I am disappointed
in where we stand. The answer is simply yes and no. Ha. Obviously,
as you look back at the season, you start to count all of the games
that we have had that were very winnable games that we just didn’t
pull out. You look at all the games in where mental errors and
basketball mistakes cost you victories. Every team can look back at
a season and point out a handful of games like these. The problem
is that we have had more than I care to count. By no means am I
throwing in the towel and quitting on the season. We still have 20
games to go. You just never know when luck breaks your way, so we
will continue to compete and try to win every game.<br />
<br />
A much more immediate goal for us is finding some consistency in
our games. We have had some great wins recently, games where
everything has just clicked. We play great defense, we make shots,
we play as a team. Unfortunately, we seem to follow up these great
games with a poor game. I don't know why, but we just have not
shown great consistency. While we are still trying to incorporate
the new guys, Kevin Martin, Hilton Armstrong, Jordan Hill, Jared
Jefferies, we still have to find consistency with our play. I guess
that aspect of the season has been the most disappointing for me. I
am a firm believer that you do what you do best, do it with energy
and togetherness, do it nightly and take your chances. If your
system and players are good enough, you will win games, if not,
then you won't, but the most important aspect of this is that you
play to a standard nightly. We are still searching for that
standard.<br />
<br />
Hopefully we will find our stride in the last 20 games. Hopefully
we can find something to build on and gain confidence. If not for
this year, at least build some momentum for next year. That is the
goal for the last month of the season.<br />
<br />
Talk to you soon,<br />
<br />
Shane]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100gzyw.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 09:36:05 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100gzyw.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>交易日</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100grh1.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><font FACE="Calibri"><font FACE="Calibri">首先，我想再次祝福大家新年愉快。我希望每个人都能享受到友情、美食和愉快的时光。姚明九年来第一次回到中国去过年。我知道，能够和亲友在一起共度佳节(大快朵颐)，他有多么开心。大家新年快乐！</FONT></FONT></P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
今天是NBA交易截止日。NBA中大部分交易都会在今天发生。每支球队都有不同的交易需求。一些球队想清理掉一些水平太低的球员或者垃圾合同，这样才可以在自由市场上签下新球员，另一些球队希望能够签下一些能够带来帮助的球员。你可能已经知道，火箭将卡尔-兰德里、乔伊-多西和特雷西-迈克格雷迪送到了萨克拉门托国王，换回了凯文-马丁和还有待确定的其他一些球员。交易永远是有失有得。一方面，我为卡尔和乔伊的离去感到难过，因为他们在更衣室里很活跃，大家相处得非常开心。他们总是带着浑身的热情来到训练馆，这一点非常少有。我相信他们在国王队会干得不错。卡尔是一颗希望之星，我希望也相信他将前程似锦。昨晚下飞机后，我告诉他，<strong>希望他继续努力训练，继续坚持用正确的方式打球，永不满足</STRONG>。这是一个多好的孩子啊。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>
我们用卡尔交易来的家伙是凯文-马丁，他是一个货真价实的优秀进攻球员。他是联盟中最难防守的后卫之一，因为他投篮非常准。如果给他空位出手的机会，他一定能够命中。他的无球跑动也非常棒，他一刻都不停地奔跑。他擅长制造犯规，而且他的罚球命中率高达90％。据和他打过球的人说，这人工作努力，是一个好队友。这点很重要，因为我们队内气氛很好，我们希望保持更衣室的和谐。凯文不会是一个在更衣室制造麻烦的人。他和其他队友能磨合到什么程度，这得上了场才会知道。每个交易发生时，在纸面上看都不错，但时间会告诉你，某项交易是帮助还是伤害了球队。如今火箭队后卫线上可谓人才济济，凯文-马丁、特里弗-阿里扎、蔡斯-巴丁格、阿隆-布鲁克斯、洛瑞和我，看看主教练怎么排兵布阵吧，这应该很有意思。我不知道球队未来的方向，希望这次交易能够让我们进入季后赛，并且等下赛季姚明复出后我们能够冲击总冠军。不要走开。这一定很有意思。</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>回头再聊朋友们，</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>肖恩</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p>原文如下——&nbsp;</P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p><font FACE="Calibri">First of all, I want to wish everyone a
happy lunar new year again. I hope everyone enjoyed themselves with
good friends, good food and good times. Yao was going to back to
China for the first time in 9 years to celebrate the New Year. I
know how excited he was to go back and spend time with family and
friends (and eat a lot of great food). Happy New Year
everyone!</FONT></P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p><font FACE="Calibri">Today is the trade deadline. Today is the
day when most of the trades in the NBA happen. Every team has a
different motivation in trading their players. Some teams want to
get rid of bad players and bad contracts so that they can sign
players in the free agent market, while others will try to trade
for players that will help their teams immediately. You may have
already read that the Rockets have traded Carl Landry, Joey Dorsey,
and Tracy McGrady to the Sacramento Kings for Kevin Martin and
other players to be determined later. Trades are always
bittersweet. On one hand, I am sad to see Carl and Joey go away,
they were great in the locker room and were always happy and
upbeat. They came to the gym with a genuine enthusiasm, which is
difficult to find believe it or not. I know they will do well in
Sacramento. Carl is a budding star, I hope he has a great career, I
know he will. I told him last night as we exited the plane to keep
working, keep playing the right way, and to stay hungry. What a
good guy.</FONT></P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p><font FACE="Calibri">The guy we traded Carl for, Kevin Martin,
is a really, really good offensive player. He is one of the tougher
guards in the league to guard because he is a very good shooter. If
he has an open shot, he will make it. He also is great moving
without the ball, he never stops moving. He creates a lot of fouls
and is a 90% free throw shooter. The guys who have played with him
say that he is a hard worker and good teammate. That is very
important, because we have a good group of guys and the last thing
we need is someone to cause trouble in the locker room. Kevin won't
be a locker room problem. As far as how he will fit in with the
rest of the team on the court remains to be seen. Every trade looks
good on paper when they happen, but only time will tell if the
trade helped or hurt the teams involved. With a logjam of players
on the wing, Kevin Martin, Trevor Ariza, Chase Budinger, Aaron
Brooks, Kyle Lowry, and myself, it will be interesting to see how
Coach tweaks the lineup. I don't know in what direction our team
will go, hopefully this move will propel us into the playoffs and
put us in a position to make a run for a championship when Yao
returns next season healthy and ready to go. Stay tuned. It should
be interesting.</FONT></P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p><font FACE="Calibri">Talk to you soon my friends,</FONT></P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>
<p><font FACE="Calibri">Shane</FONT></P>
<p>&nbsp;</P>]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100grh1.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 10:46:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100grh1.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>“Dog Days”</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100glvp.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a HREF="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static14.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253eg7e999b22f7dd" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static14.photo.sina.com.cn/middle/4b2b253eg7e999b22f7dd&amp;690" /></A><br />

<br />
我们已经进入了NBA俗称的“dog
days(三伏天)”。这指的是圣诞假期之后全明星周末之前的这段时间。在全明星周末后，你能看到漫长赛季尽头的曙光，这时候每场比赛的胜负都至关重要，所以大家都会卯足了劲。狗日子就不同了，这段时间很难熬。我们的赛程已经过半，每个人要么在与伤病搏斗要么已经精疲力竭。队中的新秀蔡斯-巴丁格问我：“我们还有40场比赛要打么？我们怎么办？”蔡斯本赛季到目前为止参加的比赛比大学任何一年都多。<br />

<br />
没必要遮遮掩掩，我们队最近的确没打出最佳状态。我们的连续六个主场，目前是1胜4负(今晚我们将迎来金州勇士)。之前我们经历了一段严酷的客场之旅，当时我们相信回到主场，有球迷的助威，我们将轻松地取得胜利。我们在与诸如鹰队、掘金和太阳等强队交手时，发挥得不够好，没有获得胜利。许多人于是都开始看衰我们，我必须提醒你们每支球队都可能经历一段低潮期，这很正常。我们知道要进入季后赛就必须和实力相当的球队殊死一搏。现在还不是指责和质疑的时候。我们必须保持团结，找到赢球的办法。<br />

<br />
我从杜克大学教练老K那里听来一个比喻，我觉得送给现在的火箭队正合适。他告诉我们——这话我也转送给了现在的队友——一支篮球队就好比一个手掌上的五根指头。当大家团结在一起时，所有手指都攥紧，形成一只强有力的拳头。(尽管我不崇尚暴力)，但在打架时，一个拳头要强过五根手指。这个比喻放到球队身上，那就是，尽管队员们天赋有高有低，但是只要大家心往一处想劲往一处使，那肯定强过各自为战。如果每根指头都自作主张不顾大局，那会导致什么后果？拳头的威力将不复存在，而且你还会手指骨折(哦！)。所以这就是团结的重要性。一支球队必须团结成一个拳头。<br />

<br />
说说我个人的事儿吧，如果火箭比赛转播你一场不落，你应该会发现我的上唇有些毛茸茸的。是的，我正在留胡子。为什么呢？因为这样看上去比较搞笑，有时候你必须拿自己开心。我的好哥们小麦克-邓利维去年就留了胡子，我不能让他一个人专美。我无意冒犯那些留胡子的人，但对我自己来说，长了胡子很搞笑。不要总那么严肃，否则你得生活会失去很多乐趣。笑一笑。笑对自己。笑对别人的嘲笑。这会让你变得更年轻！胡子会留多久？不知道，别管这个，好好享受吧。<br />

<br />
回头聊朋友们，<br />
<br />
肖恩<br />
<br />
原文如下——<br />
<br />
We are officially in what us in the NBA call the 'dog days' of the
season. It's the period after the holidays and before the All-Star
break where time seems to stand still. After the All-Star break,
you can see the light at the end of the tunnel and every game is so
important, so there is a lot of energy for these games. The 'dog
days,' however, are tough to get through. We have played more than
half the season at this point and everyone is nursing injuries to
an extent or just plain fatigued. Talking to Chase Budinger, our
great rookie, he asks me 'We still have 40 games to go? How do we
make it?" Chase has already played more games to date than he has
in any year in college.<br />
<br />
It's no secret that our team has not played its best basketball as
of late. When we pointed to this homestand of 6 games, we did not
anticipate going 1-4 (we play Golden State tonight to finish the
homestand). We had such a road heavy schedule early that was
brutal, that we assumed that when we returned home, we would win
just because we were playing in front of our home fans. While we
have played some very good teams, Atlanta, Denver, Phoenix, the
truth is that we just haven't played well enough to beat these good
teams. While many people are counting us out, I must remind you
that every team goes through a lull during the year when they just
don't play well. We know we are in a dogfight to make the playoffs
with so many teams right around us in the standings. Now is not the
time to start doubting ourselves and to point fingers. We must
continue to stay together and find a way to win games.<br />
<br />
I gave the team an analogy that I heard from my college coach,
Coach Krzyzewski at Duke University. He told us, which I told the
team, that the basketball team is like the fingers on a hand. When
a team is together and every 'finger' is in union with each other,
you can form a powerful fist. (Although I don't advocate violence),
if you are ever in a fist fight, a hand that has formed a strong
fist is much more dangerous and powerful than a hand that is not.
Much like a team that is together, working towards a common goal,
despite the talent level of the team, is much more potent and
dangerous than a team that is not. If even one finger (or player)
is not working in unison with the other fingers on the hand, what
happens? The strength and power of the fist is greatly diminished
and there is even a good possibility that you could break a finger
(ouch!). Such is the importance of working together. A team must
form a 'fist' to fight with unity.<br />
<br />
On a personal note, if you have been watching the Rockets play at
all, you have probably noticed my hairy upper lip. Yes, I have
attempted to grow a mustache. Why? Because it looks totally
ridiculous and sometimes you just have to laugh at yourself. My
best friend Mike Dunleavy Jr. of the Indiana Pacers grew (an ugly)
mustache last year and I can't let him have all the fun. I have
nothing against people with mustaches, but on me, it just looks
funny. Never take yourself or what you do too seriously that you
can't find the inherent humor in life. Laugh. Laugh at yourself.
Laugh when others laugh at you. It keeps you young! How long will
the mustache last? No one knows, just enjoy it.<br />
<br />
Talk to you soon my friends,<br />
<br />
Shane<br />
<br />]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100glvp.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 06:43:29 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100glvp.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>火箭的进攻不是问题</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100ggsn.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a HREF="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static8.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et7da37e700257&amp;690" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static8.photo.sina.com.cn/bmiddle/4b2b253et7da37e700257&amp;690" STYLE="" /></A><br />
<br />
<a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://static14.photo.sina.com.cn/orignal/4b2b253et7da392dcdc8d&amp;690" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://static14.photo.sina.com.cn/bmiddle/4b2b253et7da392dcdc8d&amp;690" STYLE="" /></A><br />
<br />
在一个赛季中，你总会有一些比赛打得不好。这就是我们球队目前的情况。我们似乎不能连续打出两场漂亮仗。在12月，我们和许多强队有过精彩的对决，到了1月份，面对实力不强的对手，我们却打得很辛苦。究竟是为什么呢？相信我们，我们想打出漂亮的比赛，每次赛前我们都希望能够四节都打出水平。我认为我们的防守强度在下降，防守的注意力也在下降，而这正是赛季初让我们取得成功的关键。一些简单的动作，比如滑步造进攻犯规、为被突破的队友补防，这些必须成为我们防守的基础。由于我们失去了姚明，队中现在没有人能够在篮下接二连三送出盖帽(当我成了球队的盖帽王时，事情就危险了，哈哈！)。我们必须依靠速度、灵活和积极性去加强我们的防守。许多人都认为我们的进攻是个问题，但我不同意。现在的情况是：只要我们整体防守做得好，那我们就可以满场飞奔，互相协助，提升比赛强度，最终进攻端也将受益。当我们做好防守，就可以迫使对手有更多失误，我们获得更多的反击，投进更多的球，发挥出更多能量。尽管听起来很奇怪，但的确对我们来说，最好的进攻就是防守。我深信不疑。<br />

<br />
按照这种说法，我相信我们队的表现将得到提升。每支球队都会有低潮期。现在还不是互相指责和挑剔的时候。现在我们应该做的是更加努力、更加团结。这才是一个出色的团队和个人在面对困难时应该做的。就像我的一位队友(<a HREF="http://blog.sina.com.cn/tariza" TARGET="_blank">阿里扎</A>)纹在身上的这句话：“Tough times don't last, tough
people do（艰难时期不会长久，能吃苦的人会笑到最后）!”<br />
<br />
我喜欢这话。<br />
<br />
回见，<br />
<br />
肖恩<br />
<br />
原文如下——<br />
<br />
During the course of a season, you are bound to play some sub-par
basketball. That is where we are right now as a basketball team. We
just can't seem to put together two good games in a row. After a
December in which we played great basketball against some great
teams, we have struggled in January to put away some of the teams
with poor records. The question is, why? Trust us, we want to play
good basketball, and we go into every game thinking that we are
going to put together 4 quarters of good hoops. I believe that our
defense has become softer and that our mental concentration on the
little aspects of defense, the aspects that we executed
successfully in the early season, has become a tad less focused.
Simple plays like sliding over to take a charge or helping your
teammate when he gets beat off the dribble must be staples our
defense. Since we lost Yao, we really don't have anyone to protect
the rim with consistent shot blocking (you know you are in trouble
when I am the leading shotblocker, ha!). We must rely on speed,
quickness, and anticipation to play strong team defense. Many
people think that our offense is the issue, but I would disagree
with those people. What happens with our team is that when we play
great team defense and we are flying all over the court, helping
each other and playing with great intensity, it carries over the
offensive end. When we are amped up on defense, we tend to create
more turnovers, get out on the break more, shoot better, and play
with a better level of energy. It is strange to say, but our best
offense is a good defense. I truly believe that.<br />
<br />
With that said, I am confident that we will improve our play. Every
team goes though a bit of a slump. Now is not the time to point
fingers or place blame. Now is the time to work harder and become
even more together as a team. That is what good teams and good
individuals do during the tough times. As the tatoo reads on one of
my teammates arm "Tough times don't last, tough people do!"<br />
<br />
I like that.<br />
<br />
Talk to you soon,<br />
<br />
shane<br />
<br />]]></description>
            <author>battierblog</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100ggsn.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 10:30:44 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b2b253e0100ggsn.html</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
