<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!-- generator="FEEDCREATOR_VERSION" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:sns="http://blog.sina.com.cn/sns">
    <channel>
        <title>郑欣宜的BLOG</title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/zhengxinyi</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 02:25:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>FEEDCREATOR_VERSION</generator>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 1996 - 2009 SINA Inc. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 15:11:40 +0800</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title>你聽到嗎？</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b0e19ef0100v0vp.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[過去的母親節我參加了一個母親節派對，負責唱歌，擔任表演嘉賓。那天的氣氛很溫馨！有已經做了父母的大朋友陪著媽媽一起去玩，有很小很小的小朋友拖著媽媽的手一起參加...但最讓我感動的是看到一些跟我年紀差不多，抱著媽媽一起大笑的年輕人。
<div><br /></DIV>
<div>母親節派對很自然我的焦點是放在媽媽們身上。看到年輕人抱著媽媽第一個反應是，“被子女抱著的媽媽是多幸福呀”
但再看就對自己說，“能抱著媽媽的子女是多幸福呢..."</DIV>
<div><br /></DIV>
<div>雖然我知道我沒有機會再陪著媽媽一起去玩，也沒有機會再去緊緊地拖著她的手...雖然我知道我再也沒有機會抱著她說，”i love
you“...
但我知道在天國的她一定能夠聽到我的歌。所以在母親節派對上我唱了專輯上的一首《夢飛行》。除了送給在場的媽媽們我也希望送這首歌給我最偉大，只有為我付出的媽媽。</DIV>
<div><br /></DIV>
<div><font COLOR="#6F3198">Mom, happy
mother's day. I love you and miss you always.</FONT>
<b><i><font COLOR="#6F3198">"我牽著你的手雨打風吹也不說後悔...一直往前飛人生一起體會...
因為愛一切都完美”...</FONT></I></B></DIV>
<div>
<div><b><i><br /></I></B></DIV>
<div><span STYLE="font-style: normal; font-weight: normal;">（只有彩排片段希望大家不介意！）</SPAN></DIV>
<div><span STYLE="font-style: normal; font-weight: normal;"><div><object id="articlevblog" width="482" height="388" > <param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /> <embed pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" src="http://vhead.blog.sina.com.cn/player/outer_player.swf?auto=0</embed></object></div></SPAN></DIV>
<div><span STYLE="font-style: normal; font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://s1.sinaimg.cn/orignal/4b0e19efga2dc4fc82240" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://s1.sinaimg.cn/small/4b0e19efga2dc4fc82240&amp;690" NAME="image_operate_16011304967992888" /></A><a href="http://blog.photo.sina.com.cn/showpic.html#url=http://s11.sinaimg.cn/orignal/4b0e19efga2dc50a7ac9a" TARGET="_blank"><img SRC="http://s11.sinaimg.cn/small/4b0e19efga2dc50a7ac9a&amp;690" NAME="image_operate_64541304967995678" /></A><br />
<br /></SPAN></DIV>
<div><br /></DIV>
</DIV>]]></description>
            <author>郑欣宜</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b0e19ef0100v0vp.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 02:25:12 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b0e19ef0100v0vp.html</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Banana香蕉</title>
            <link>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b0e19ef01000845.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<DIV>&nbsp;</DIV>
<DIV><A HREF="http://album.sina.com.cn/pic/4b0e19ef02000ops" TARGET="_blank"><IMG STYLE="WIDTH: 520px; HEIGHT: 390px" SRC="http://album.sina.com.cn/pic/4b0e19ef02000ops" BORDER="0"></A></DIV>
<DIV>&nbsp;
<P CLASS="MsoNormal"></P>
<P>This is a bruised, painfully yellow, decaying banana. When I
found it, it was sitting shamefully at the top of a beautiful
crystal bowl filled with a colorful array of fruits. The firm,
spotless, just-bought bunch of bananas beneath it was making a
mockery of its blemishes and imperfections. I probably would’ve
left it to mould and opted for an orange or an apple instead had it
not been for the overconfidence those flawless bananas exuded. Left
on its own by its fellow “bunch-mates”, this banana stood out but
was certainly a wrinkle in an otherwise perfect picture of
beauty.</P>
<P>
这是一个已经有斑的，蔫黄的，快要烂了的香蕉。我看到的时候，它害羞的坐在一堆五颜六色的水果顶上，一起被放在一个非常美丽的水晶果盘当中。它的底下放着一堆还有些硬的，皮上没有斑的，刚买来的一挂香蕉，似乎在嘲笑它的斑点和缺陷。我就让它自己发霉去，改为选一个苹果或者桔子来吃，也使得那些新鲜香蕉不那么过分自信。把它留在这堆香蕉旁边，他显然成为本来是一幅完美图画的一道显眼的皱纹。</P>
<P>I guess in a way I felt for that teased and taunted banana. I
suddenly felt obligated to defend that banana. So I picked the
lonely, outcast-banana over the gang of handsome bananas. I picked
the speckled, hurting banana because I knew that those other
bananas were swollen with pride and needed to be taught a lesson…
and it was about time the ridiculed banana got some positive
attention.</P>
<P>
我猜这根香蕉一定受到了嘲笑和羞辱，我突然觉得自己有责任去保护它。于是我在这群英俊的香蕉中，独独拿起了这根孤独的被抛弃的香蕉。我之所以选它，是因为我觉得其他的香蕉过于自负，应该被好好教训一下，而且被嘲笑的香蕉也应该获得一些注意力。</P>
<P>When I reached out to rescue that banana from the fruit bowl, I
hesitated at first. I wasn’t sure I wanted to touch the spongy
film of what’s left of its skin – but after seeing the smug
shades of yellow those other bananas had turned, I took a deep
breath and went in for it.</P>
<P>
当我要把那个香蕉从果盘中拯救出来的时候，一开始我犹豫了。我不确定自己是不是要真的去碰那些看上去有些腐烂的香蕉皮。但是看到其他香蕉样样得意的样子，我深呼吸了一口气，走上前。</P>
<P>I held my breath and peeled back a section of the ugly banana
peel…</P>
<P>我摒住呼吸，剥开了看上去烂烂的那部分香蕉皮…</P>
<P><A HREF="http://album.sina.com.cn/pic/4b0e19ef02000opt" TARGET="_blank"><IMG SRC="http://album.sina.com.cn/pic/4b0e19ef02000opt" BORDER="0"></A></P>
<P>… I let go of that little puff of air I had reserved, eyebrows
raised with surprise…</P>
<P>我松了口气，惊奇的抬了抬眉毛</P>
<P><A HREF="http://album.sina.com.cn/pic/4b0e19ef02000opu" TARGET="_blank"><IMG SRC="http://album.sina.com.cn/pic/4b0e19ef02000opu" BORDER="0"></A></P>
<P>Peeled（剥好了）</P>
<P>&nbsp;</P>
<P>The flesh of the banana was plump and pure. No imperfections -
not even a single strand of that chalky inner peel was left on the
inside of the fruit.</P>
<P>
香蕉肉饱满又干净，没有一点不完美，甚至皮里面的白色果膜也没有留在香蕉肉上。</P>
<P>This is when I realized I had made the right decision when I
chose to save this banana. This was its moment of glory, it knew
that it was better than those raw bananas still sitting in the
bowl. It knew that the others would’ve been bland, dry and stiff
– but it knew that it was going to be fragrant, juicy and tender.
Yes – it was the banana’s moment of glory!!! To celebrate? Ate
it.</P>
<P>
这是我觉得选择这个香蕉是多么的明智啊。这是它的荣耀时刻，它知道自己比那些还在果盘里面还夹生的香蕉要棒的多！它知道那些香蕉可能还有些生涩，有点干硬-但是它自己是芳香多汁软软的。没错，这就是一个香蕉的光辉时刻。庆祝一下吧？咬一口！</P>
<P>Hahahaha~ THE END</P>
<P>哈哈哈哈，全文完</P>
<P>&nbsp;</P>
</DIV>
]]></description>
            <author>郑欣宜</author>
            <comments>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b0e19ef01000845.html#comment</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 10:24:46 +0800</pubDate>
            <guid>http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4b0e19ef01000845.html</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
